

# Dan **Ornelas**

## **TECHNICAL SUPPORT ANALYST**

Technician with 15 years of professional career in information technology, with a career focused on the solution of technical problems and quality customer service. Noted for my prioritization and effective communication skills, as well as my ability to solve complex problems efficiently. A collaborative approach and my commitment to quality service have been fundamental in my professional career, always in search of continuous improvement and excellence in every interaction with customers.

## CONTACT



(52) 55 1365 1294



dan-ornelas@outlook.com



www.linkedin.com/in/danornelas

## LANGUAGES

- Basic English
- Native Spanish

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Frubana

DEVOPS & DATA Technical Support Analyst II July 2023 - October 2024

Attention to incidents in the services, equipment and systems of the warehouse operation. Attention to Tickets for IT support. Attention to channel reports of incidents in different services to the corresponding areas for follow-up and resolution.

# **Hewlett Packard Enterprise**

Technical Solution Consultant I June 2022 - August 2023

Specialist in Remote Support for HPE servers for customers in Latin America, in charge of diagnosing reactive events at the Hardware level and providing appropriate solutions, in addition to providing telephone assistance to the end customer for Hardware compatibility queries and configuration and installation of Supported Operating Systems.

#### Frubana

**Technical Support Analyst** 

October 2021 - July 2022

Attention to incidents in the services, equipment and systems of the warehouse operation, assistance for diagnosis and routing of technical service reports with service providers to office printing equipment, and warehouse CCTV system.

# GTC Global Technology Corporation S.A. de CV.

IT Support Engineer

February 2021 - June 2021

Specialist in face-to-face and remote technical support, in the IT department for staff attention within the Corporate and in the different offices belonging to Banorte Insurance and Pensions. Responsible for providing diagnosis and solution to the different technical problems in the users' equipment, installation of Software and replacement and installation of Hardware, configuration and customization of equipment for renewal.

## **SKILLS**

- Prioritize work
- Communication skills and service attitude
- Ease of learning (Self-taught)
- Investigative and problem-solving skills
- Ticket Management Systems
- Hardware Diagnostics and Repair
- Basic knowledge in networks
- Basic knowledge of audio and video editing
- Basic knowledge of Programming (JS, HTML and Python)

## **COURSES**

- Al productivity hacks
- Generative Al Fundamentals
- HPE Proliant servers Gen 8
- HPE Proliant servers Gen 9
- HPE Blade System
- HPE Virtual Connect
- HPE OneView
- HPE Proliant servers Gen 10
- HPE 3PAR Installation
- Cybersecurity
- Linux Fundamentals
- Emotional intelligence
- Quality of Service
- Computer Technician (Office Automation)
- Computer Equipment Installation and Repair Technician

# **Hewlett Packard Enterprise**

Technical Solution Consultant I (Spain HPE CSC) June 2018 - July 2019

Specialist in Remote Support for HPE servers and Storage for customers in Spain, in charge of diagnosing reactive events at the Hardware level and providing appropriate solutions, in addition to providing telephone assistance to the end customer for Hardware compatibility queries and configuration and installation of Supported Operating Systems.

# **Hewlett Packard Enterprise**

Technical Solution Consultant I

April 2015 - June 2018

Specialist in Remote Support for HPE servers for customers in Latin America, in charge of diagnosing reactive events at the Hardware level and providing appropriate solutions, in addition to providing telephone assistance to the end customer for Hardware compatibility queries and configuration and installation of Supported Operating Systems.

# Computación Alfa

Technical Consultant January 2009 – January 2012

Technical support for office and home computer equipment, preventive and corrective maintenance of Hardware and Software, cleaning and replacement of Components for printers, office automation, advanced knowledge of Windows.

# **EDUCATION**

**ACADEMLO** 

Full-Stack Web Development and Computer Science

E.S.I.M.E. Culhuacán Communication and Electronics Engineering Trunca (2009 - 2010)